hey everybody welcome to this b1 english
listening practice video you can use
this video to practice your listening
and comprehension as i speak before we
start remember to download the listening
time podcast and become a member at
patreon.comlisteningtime
to receive my listening practice
seminars sound training videos and extra
podcast episodes and remember that if
you become a listening time family
member you'll also receive my advanced
podcast episodes ok today i'm going to
talk about american culture i could
probably talk for hours and hours about
this topic but i'll try to cover a few
main cultural elements and then i'll
probably do a part two to this video so
let's just jump right in the u.s has
what most people would probably consider
the most popular culture in the world
this is due to the fact that the us
exports its culture to other countries
via the internet entertainment and other
means and the fact that english is now
the most important language for business
and travel has also contributed to this
so a lot of you probably already know
quite a bit about american culture but
let's go ahead and talk about a few
cultural elements one of the most
important aspects of american culture is
our commitment to freedom one of the
most important values in the us if not
the most important is personal liberty
at the very core of the us constitution
and the declaration of independence is
the idea that each individual has the
right to live freely and the government
only exists to protect this right so
what does this mean exactly it means
that individual people can live and act
how they want as long as they don't
infringe upon the rights of others in
the u.s we stress the individual more
than the collective this is different
from most countries where there's more
stress on the common good of society in
these places the government often has a
bigger influence in people's lives okay
the next cultural element i want to talk
about is politeness when many foreigners
visit the us they notice that while it
may not be the friendliest country in
the world americans tend to be very
polite for example we have a tendency to
say things in a pretty indirect way to
sound nicer so if we're at a restaurant
instead of asking the waiter where's the
restroom most of us would probably say
could you tell me where the restroom is
these types of indirect questions sound
more polite so we prefer them in certain
situations if someone asks something
very directly many americans might even
feel that that person's being a little
rude this is indicative of how much
politeness is valued in the u.s all
right one other cultural element that i
want to discuss is the entrepreneurship
in the u.s this obviously exists in
every country but the entrepreneurial
spirit is especially widespread in the
us many people dream of owning their own
business or creating something new a lot
of my students in other countries tell
me that only a small minority of people
in their country want to become an
entrepreneur most people would probably
prefer to work as an employee and a good
company with good benefits of course
many americans want this too but there
are also many people that want to start
something on their own there's something
about creating a business from scratch
that's really appealing and inspiring to
many people and some people simply value
independence more than comfort i'm
definitely this type of person
considering that i've never worked a
full-time job as an employee even though
i've never received benefits like paid
vacation days i still prefer this style
of work i love the freedom and
excitement that comes with working
independently and as an entrepreneur so
you could definitely say that i have
this entrepreneurial spirit in me okay
that's all for today i'll probably make
a part 2 to this video to talk about
some more cultural elements in the us
before you go make sure to download the
listening time podcast and become a
member at patreon.com listeningtime to
receive my listening practice seminars
sound training videos and bonus podcast
episodes and remember that if you become
a listening time family member you'll
receive my advanced podcast episodes
also subscribe to the channel click on
the bell and follow us on instagram i'll
see you next time
[Music]